Contact

nicole.m.gorecki@gmail.com

www.linkedin.com/in/nicolecallsen (LinkedIn)

Top Skills

Nursing Care
Nursing Process
Critical Thinking

Languages

English (Native or Bilingual) Spanish (Limited Working)

Certifications

ACLS Certified

Adult Gerontology Acute Care Nurse Practitioner (AGACNP-BC)

CPR Certified

NIH Stroke Scale Certified Certified Critical-Care Registered Nurse (CCRN)

Publications

Naloxone Use in Illinois

Nicole Gorecki MSN, APRN, AGACNP-BC, CCRN

Critical Care Nurse Practitioner at Baylor University Medical Center Flower Mound, Texas

Summary

Experienced and dedicated Adult-Gerontology Acute Care Nurse Practitioner with proven skills delivering high quality, holistic care to a variety of patient populations. Extensive clinical experience in diverse healthcare settings including critical care, cardiology, cardiovascular surgery, transplant surgery and hospital medicine. Current doctoral student, committed to using evidence-based practice to promote health and manage disease. Hardworking and compassionate with excellent communication, critical thinking and interpersonal skills.

Experience

Baylor University Medical Center North Texas Critical Care Nurse Practitioner May 2020 - Present (2 months) Dallas, Texas, United States

Chamberlain University
Visiting Professor
June 2018 - Present (2 years 1 month)
Addison, Illinois

Teach critical care, collaborative health care and leadership courses in the clinical setting and in SIM lab for undergraduate nursing students.

Loyola Medicine

Intra-Abdominal Transplant Surgery Nurse Practitioner April 2019 - March 2020 (1 year)

• As an advanced practice led service, managed total care for intra-abdominal transplant surgery patients from admission to post-operatively in the surgical intensive care unit, to discharge. Patient population included those undergoing surgical procedures such as kidney, liver and/or pancreas transplants, donor nephrectomies, as well as any readmissions for up to 1 year post-transplant.

- Clinical documentation including history and physicals, consultations, progress notes and discharge summaries.
- Closely examined each patient's medical history, family history, allergies, physical condition, and test results to determine the appropriate plan of care.
- Collaborated with consulted medical specialties and ancillary staff such as pharmacy, case management, physical, occupational and speech therapies, nutrition, and spiritual care to develop and implement a plan of care unique to each patient's needs.
- Ordered and executed diagnostic tests and analyzed images to further investigate patient conditions.
- Developed an open rapport with both patients and their families, encouraging them to share questions and concerns.
- Provided support and guidance for both Loyola and visiting medical students, as well as Advanced Practice nursing students.
- Epic "TogetherCare" Super User, assisting end-users to navigate through the system and answer their questions/trouble shoot any problems that may arise.

Elgin Community College Adjunct Nursing Professor August 2018 - March 2020 (1 year 8 months)

Teach nursing concepts IV in the clinical setting and in SIM lab for undergraduate nursing students.

Northwestern Memorial Hospital Advanced Practice Fellow October 2018 - March 2019 (6 months)

Chicago, Illinois

- Northwestern Medicine John R. Flanagan Advanced Practice Fellowship, a 6-month intensive post-graduate acute care fellowship program with both clinical training and a rigorous didactic curriculum, paired with attending physicians in the hospital medicine and cardiology specialties, including advanced heart failure and heart transplant patients.
- Clinical documentation included history and physicals, consultations, progress notes and discharge summaries.
- Closely examined each patient's medical history, family history, allergies, physical condition, and test results to determine the appropriate plan of care.
- Collaborated with consulted medical specialties and ancillary staff such as pharmacy, case management, physical, occupational and speech therapies, nutrition, and spiritual care to develop and implement a plan of care unique to each patient's needs.

 Ordered and executed diagnostic tests and analyzed images to further investigate patient conditions.

Advocate Sherman Hospital
Registered Nurse
August 2014 - September 2018 (4 years 2 months)
Elgin, Illinois

- Team member of the Critical Care Unit.
- Possess advanced multi-tasking skills while delivering safe and quality critical nursing care under high stress situations.
- Perform specialized nursing care involving titrating drip intravenous infusions, inserting midline intravenous catheters and arterial lines, managing patients requiring mechanical ventilation, therapeutic hypothermia, RotoProne therapy, intra-aortic balloon pump (IABP) therapy, continuous renal replacement therapy (CRRT), and extracorporeal membrane oxygenation (ECMO).
- Assisting clinicians in sterile invasive bedside procedures, caring for surgical and/or cardiovascular patients including angiogram, thoracotomy, carotid endarterectomy, valve repair, femoral-popliteal bypass, aortic aneurysm, Whipple, liver resection, and pre-operative open heart surgical patients.
- Provide support and guidance as a preceptor for Registered Nurses new to critical care and/or Advocate Health care as well as precept students in nursing (RN) programs.

University of Chicago Medicine Nurse Extern June 2013 - July 2014 (1 year 2 months) Chicago, IL

- Team member of the Pediatric Intensive Care Unit.
- Assist the Registered Nurse in patient care activities, ranging from 1:1 ICUstatus to intermediate-care patients.

Education

Illinois State University-Mennonite College of Nursing Doctor of Nursing Practice - DNP · (2018 - 2021)

Loyola University Chicago

Master of Science in Nursing with Honors, Adult-Gerontology Acute Care Nurse Practitioner · (2015 - 2018)

Saint Xavier University

Bachelor of Science in Nursing, Honors Scholar, Psychology

Minor · (2010 - 2014)